John Moors Cabot Papers MS110
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
John Moors Cabot Papers
1909 -- 1981
1940 -- 1969
Digital Collections and Archives, Tufts University
Cabot, John Moors
MS110
30.48 Linear Feet 24 boxes and 1 oversized folder
Arrangement
This collection is organized into five series: Correspondence and subject files; Personal records; Photographs; Physical memorabilia; Newspaper clippings.
Scope and Contents
This collection consists of the professional and personal papers of the Ambassador John Moors Cabot between 1929 and 1980. Included in the collection are diaries, correspondence, photographs, scrapbooks, newspaper clippings, writings, oral histories, artifacts, and audiovisual materials. The materials document Cabot's professional life, including his activities as an American Ambassador, and his personal life. Cabot's professional activities in numerous countries—including Argentina, Brazil, Colombia, China, Guatemala, Poland, San Salvador, Sweden, and Yugoslavia—are noted in this collection. Other topics include Cabot's publishing efforts, correspondence relating to the Maria Moors Cabot Prize, and his interactions with Tufts University.
Biographical / Historical
John Moors Cabot was born in Cambridge, Massachusetts on December 11, 1901. The son of prominent Bostonians, Godfrey Lowell Cabot (founder of Cabot Corporation) and Maria Moors Cabot, John Cabot attended Buckingham Browne & Nichols School (Cambridge) and the Pomfret School (Connecticut). He graduated from Harvard University in 1923 (A.B.) magnum cum laude, and from Brasenose College, of Oxford University in 1925 (B.Litt), with a degree in Modern History.
In 1926, Cabot joined the United States Foreign Service and eventually served as an ambassador to Sweden (1954-1957), Columbia (1957-1959), Brazil (1959-1961), and Poland (1962-1965), among other prominent diplomatic appointments in Peru, the Dominican Republic, the Netherlands, Mexico, China, Guatemala, Yugoslavia, and Argentina. From 1953-1954 he served as Assistant Secretary of State for Inter-American Affairs. In 1956, Cabot received an honorary doctorate degree from Tufts University and spoke at the commencement ceremony. He was involved in discussions regarding many of the most serious issues of the time, such as the Alliance for Progress, the Bay of Pigs invasion and others. He retired from government service in 1966 and began lecturing at the Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy at Tufts University, as well as the School of Foreign Service at Georgetown University.
John M. Cabot published a book titled 'The Racial Conflict in Transylvania: A Discussion of the Conflicting Claims of Rumania and Hungary to Transylvania, the Banat, and the Eastern Section of the Hungarian Plain' in 1926. John M. Cabot married Elizabeth Lewis in 1932 and had four children: John G.L. Cabot, Lewis P. Cabot, Marjorie (Cabot) Enriquez, and Elizabeth T. (Cabot) van Wentzel. Cabot died in February 1981.
Conditions Governing Access
This collection is open for research.
Foreign affairs; Ambassadors -- United States; Cabot, John Moors
- Correspondence and Subject Files, 1927 -- 1981; MS110.001; 12.0 Linear Feet
  Scope and Contents
  This series contains correspondence of the Ambassador. These letters include topics of diplomacy in Argentina, Brazil, Columbia, Stockholm, Swedan, Shanghai, Washington D.C., Yugoslavia and other counties. As well as containing embassy correspondence, this series contains correspondence relating to the Maria Moors Cabot Prize and personal correspondence.
  Arrangement
  This series is arranged alphabetically by first word, then chronologically
  Conditions Governing Access
  Open for research.
  - Argentina: Buenos Aires Correspondence, 1945; MS110.001.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Argentina: Buenos Aires Correspondence, 1946; MS110.001.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Argentina: Embassy Correspondence, 1945 -- 1946; MS110.001.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Argentina: Embassy Correspondence/Speeches, 1945 -- 1946; MS110.001.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - "The Belize Question" paper, 1940 -- 1943; MS110.001.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, May - June, 1959; MS110.001.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, July - September, 1959; MS110.001.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, October - December, 1959; MS110.001.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Declassified Documents, July 17- December, 1959; MS110.001.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Speeches, Folder 1 of 2, 1959; MS110.001.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Speeches, Folder 2 of 2, 1959; MS110.001.001.00011 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, January - May, 1960; MS110.001.001.00012 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, June - November, 1960; MS110.001.001.00013 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, November - December, 1960; MS110.001.001.00014 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: News Clippings, reports, speeches, press releases, 1960; MS110.001.001.00015 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Declassified Documents, 1960; MS110.001.001.00016 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Speeches, 1960; MS110.001.001.00017 (Box 1)
  - Brazil: Speeches, 1960; MS110.001.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Report on Medicine in Latin America, Africa, and Asia, 1960; MS110.001.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, December- February and January., 1960 -- 1961; MS110.001.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, February, 1961; MS110.001.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, March, 1961; MS110.001.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, April - June, 1961; MS110.001.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, July - September, 1961; MS110.001.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Declassified Documents, January - August, 1961; MS110.001.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Speeches, 1946 -- 1966; MS110.001.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Brazil: Letters from visitors to embassy, 1961; MS110.001.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - China: Embassy / Personal Correspondence, January - May, 1948; MS110.001.002.00011 (Box 2)
  - China: Shanghai--Embassy Correspondence June - September, 1948; MS110.001.002.00012 (Box 2)
  - China: Shanghai--Embassy Correspondence, October - December, January - February., 1948 -- 1949; MS110.001.002.00013 (Box 2)
  - China: Shanghai--Declassified Correspondence, 1948; MS110.001.002.00014 (Box 2)
  - China: Shanghai--Correspondence, January - March, with related material from April - December, 1949; MS110.001.002.00015 (Box 2)
  - China: Shanghai--Speeches / Articles, 1948 -- 1949; MS110.001.002.00016 (Box 2)
  - China: Shanghai--Vouchers, Telegrams, Forms, and correspondence, 1947 -- 1950; MS110.001.002.00017 (Box 2)
  - China, Proposed Trip: Correspondence, Articles, Magazines, Reports, 1980; MS110.001.002.00018 (Box 2)
  - Columbia: Speeches, 1957 -- 1959; MS110.001.002.00019 (Box 2)
  - Columbia: Pamphlets, Correspondence, Reports, Articles, 1957 -- 1959; MS110.001.002.00020 (Box 2)
  - Columbia (Bogata): Embassy Correspondence / Transition, 1957; MS110.001.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Columbia Declassified Docments, 1957; MS110.001.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Embassy Correspondence, January - April., 1958; MS110.001.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Embassy Correspondence, October - December., 1958; MS110.001.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Embassy Correspondence, 1958; MS110.001.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Declassified Documents, 1958; MS110.001.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Embassy Correspondence, January - February., 1959; MS110.001.003.00007 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Embassy Correspondence, March - April., 1959; MS110.001.003.00008 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Embassy Correspondence, May - July., 1959; MS110.001.003.00009 (Box 3)
  - Columbia: Declassified Documents, January - July 14., 1959; MS110.001.003.00010 (Box 3)
  - Committee on Present Danger: Correspondence, Reports, Press Releases., 1976 -- 1978; MS110.001.003.00011 (Box 3)
  - Conference, Regional: Foreign Policy - Pittsburgh, June 17., 1965; MS110.001.003.00012 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1936 -- 1946; MS110.001.003.00013 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Family Geneology, 1936 -- 1949; MS110.001.003.00014 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Family, 1942 -- 1959; MS110.001.003.00015 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Folder 1, 1946 -- 1959; MS110.001.003.00016 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Folder 2, 1946 -- 1959; MS110.001.003.00017 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Family- Godfrey (Father) and Tom (Brother), 1938 -- 1958; MS110.001.003.00018 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Invitations, 1955 -- 1959; MS110.001.003.00019 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Invitations, Folder 1, 1960; MS110.001.003.00020 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal: Invitations, Folder 2, 1960; MS110.001.003.00021 (Box 3)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1960 -- 1969; MS110.001.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1970 -- 1974; MS110.001.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - Correspondence, Personal, 1975 -- 1980; MS110.001.004.00003 (Box 4)
  - Dominican Republic: Revolution, 1929 -- 1931; MS110.001.004.00004 (Box 4)
  - Dulles, John Foster Oral History Project - Princeton University, 1965 -- 1966; MS110.001.004.00005 (Box 4)
  - Editors and Publishers: Correspondence, 1962 -- 1967; MS110.001.004.00006 (Box 4)
  - Finland: Personal / Embassy Correspondence, 1950 -- 1951; MS110.001.004.00007 (Box 4)
  - Finland: Embassy Correspondence, Mrs. Roosevelt's visit., 1950 -- 1952; MS110.001.004.00008 (Box 4)
  - Finland: Embassy Correspondence and Speeches, 1950 -- 1952; MS110.001.004.00009 (Box 4)
  - Finland: Embassy Correspondence, December- March, 1951 -- 1953; MS110.001.004.00010 (Box 4)
  - Finland: Visit, 1964; MS110.001.004.00011 (Box 4)
  - First Line of Defense: Georgetown University Correspondence, 1978 -- 1981; MS110.001.004.00012 (Box 4)
    Autobiography, Memoirs
  - First Line of Defense: Jay Gold Correspondence, 1975 -- 1978; MS110.001.004.00013 (Box 4)
  - First Line of Defense: Copied Chapters with Cabot's Personal Notes, MS110.001.004.00014 (Box 4)
    Autobiography, Memoirs. No Date Available
  - First Line of Defense: Manuscript Chapters, pages 1-118, MS110.001.004.00015 (Box 4)
    Autobiography, Memoirs. No date available.
  - First Line of Defense: Manuscript Chapters, pages 118-241, MS110.001.004.00016 (Box 4)
  - First Line of Defense: Manuscript Chapters, pages 281-317, 345-425, MS110.001.004.00017 (Box 4)
  - First Line of Defense: Revised Manuscript Chapters, Introduction - Chapter Six, 1970; MS110.001.005.00001 (Box 5)
    Autobiography, Memoirs. Date is approximate
  - First Line of Defense: Revised Manuscript Chapters, Chapter Seven - Afterthoughts, 1970; MS110.001.005.00002 (Box 5)
    Autobiography, Memoirs.
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy: Correspondence, 1955; MS110.001.005.00003 (Box 5)
  - Fletcher School of Law and Diplomacy: Correspondence, 1962 -- 1964; MS110.001.005.00004 (Box 5)
  - Global Correspondence, Speeches, 1934 -- 1939; MS110.001.005.00005 (Box 5)
  - Global Correspondence, Reports, Papers, 1940 -- 1949; MS110.001.005.00006 (Box 5)
  - Global Correspondence, News clippings, Reports, 1950 -- 1959; MS110.001.005.00007 (Box 5)
  - Global Speeches by Cabot, 1958 -- 1964; MS110.001.005.00008 (Box 5)
  - Global Correspondence, Clippings, Speeches, Reports, Papers; Folder 1, 1960 -- 1969; MS110.001.005.00009 (Box 5)
  - Global Correspondence, Clippings, Speeches, Reports, Papers; Folder 2, 1960 -- 1969; MS110.001.005.00010 (Box 5)
  - Global Correspondence, Reports, Clippings, Articles, 1970 -- 1979; MS110.001.005.00011 (Box 5)
  - Global Correspondence, Clippings, Speeches, Reports, Clippings; Folder 1, MS110.001.005.00012 (Box 5)
    No Date Available
  - Global Correspondence, Clippings, Speeches, Reports, Clippings; Folder 2, MS110.001.005.00013 (Box 5)
  - Guatemala: Personal/ Embassy Correspondence, with Related Material, 1927 -- 1954; MS110.001.005.00014 (Box 5)
  - Harvard: Correspondence, Class Reunions, 1970 -- 1978; MS110.001.005.00015 (Box 5)
  - Latin America: Speeches, 1950 -- 1954; MS110.001.005.00016 (Box 5)
  - Maine Teachers Association and Springbrook High School: Correspondence, 1966; MS110.001.005.00017 (Box 5)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Institutions, Rules, Winners, 1938; MS110.001.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize, 1936 -- 1937; MS110.001.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1938; MS110.001.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1939 -- 1940; MS110.001.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1941 -- 1943; MS110.001.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1944 -- 1949; MS110.001.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1950 -- 1951; MS110.001.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1952; MS110.001.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1953 -- 1955; MS110.001.006.00009 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1956 -- 1959; MS110.001.006.00010 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1962 -- 1973; MS110.001.006.00011 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Correspondence, 1974 -- 1980; MS110.001.006.00012 (Box 6)
  - Maria Moors Cabot Prize: Historical Report / Thesis, 1938 -- 1969; MS110.001.006.00013 (Box 6)
  - Marshall, General George C. Park Dedication: Correspondence, 1966; MS110.001.007.00001 (Box 7)
  - Oral Reminiscence of John M. Cabot - Fletcher School, 1971 -- 1973; MS110.001.007.00002 (Box 7)
  - Pakistan: Papers Relating to Appointment, 1952 -- 1953; MS110.001.007.00003 (Box 7)
  - Panama Canal: Clippings, Papers, Reports, 1977; MS110.001.007.00004 (Box 7)
  - Pan American Society of New England, 1936 -- 1968; MS110.001.007.00005 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, January - April., 1962; MS110.001.007.00006 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, May - June., 1962; MS110.001.007.00007 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, July - December., 1962; MS110.001.007.00008 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Declassified Documents, 1962; MS110.001.007.00009 (Box 7)
  - Poland: News Bulletins, Speeches, Press Releases, Correspondence, Notes, 1962 -- 1964; MS110.001.007.00010 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Speeches, 1962 -- 1965; MS110.001.007.00011 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, January - February., 1963; MS110.001.007.00012 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, March - June., 1963; MS110.001.007.00013 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, July - December., 1963; MS110.001.007.00014 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, January - May., 1964; MS110.001.007.00015 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, June., 1964; MS110.001.007.00016 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, July - October., 1964; MS110.001.007.00017 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, November - December., 1964; MS110.001.007.00018 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, January - June., 1965; MS110.001.007.00019 (Box 7)
  - Poland: Embassy Correspondence, July - August., 1965; MS110.001.007.00020 (Box 7)
  - Publications, 1945 -- 1959; MS110.001.008.00001 (Box 8)
  - Publications, 1960 -- 1964; MS110.001.008.00002 (Box 8)
  - Publications, 1964 -- 1977; MS110.001.008.00003 (Box 8)
  - Publications: Thesis by Juan Cabot Enriquez, March, 1981; MS110.001.008.00004 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, February - December, August., 1954 -- 1955; MS110.001.008.00005 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm, Sweden: Embassy Correspondence, March - September., 1954; MS110.001.008.00006 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence / Articles / Speeches, January - February., 1955; MS110.001.008.00007 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, March., 1955; MS110.001.008.00008 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, April - August., 1955; MS110.001.008.00009 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, September - October., 1955; MS110.001.008.00010 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, November - December., 1955; MS110.001.008.00011 (Box 8)
  - Stockholm: Declassified Documents, 1955; MS110.001.009.00001 (Box 9)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, January - February., 1954 -- 1956; MS110.001.009.00002 (Box 9)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, February - April., 1956; MS110.001.009.00003 (Box 9)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, April - July., 1956; MS110.001.009.00004 (Box 9)
  - Stockholm: Embassy/ Personal Correspondence, August - December., 1956; MS110.001.009.00005 (Box 9)
  - Stockholm: Declassified Documents, 1956; MS110.001.009.00006 (Box 9)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence, January - April., 1957; MS110.001.009.00007 (Box 9)
  - Stockholm: Embassy Correspondence / Declassified Swedish Documents, April - December., 1957; MS110.001.009.00008 (Box 9)
  - UNCIO - United Nations Conference of International Organization, Folder 1, 1944 -- 1945; MS110.001.009.00009 (Box 9)
  - UNCIO - United Nations Conference of International Organization, Folder 2, 1945; MS110.001.009.00010 (Box 9)
  - U.S. Department of State Holdings: Correspondence, Personal Files, Vouchers, Certificates., 1953 -- 1966; MS110.001.009.00011 (Box 9)
  - Washington D.C.: Lecture Tour / World Affairs Council / Selection Board, 1949 -- 1950; MS110.001.009.00012 (Box 9)
  - Washington D.C.: Eisenhower Inauguration / Trip to Mexico, January., 1953; MS110.001.009.00013 (Box 9)
  - Washington D.C.: Embassy Correspondence, February, November., 1952 -- 1953; MS110.001.009.00014 (Box 9)
  - Washington D.C.: Declassified Documents, February - December., 1953; MS110.001.009.00015 (Box 9)
  - Washington D.C.: Embassy Correspondence, March., 1953; MS110.001.009.00016 (Box 9)
  - Washington D.C.: Embassy Correspondence, April - December., 1953; MS110.001.010.00001 (Box 10)
  - Washington D.C.: Speeches, Articles, Papers, 1953; MS110.001.010.00002 (Box 10)
  - Washington D.C.: Articles, Notes, Correspondence, Speeches, Folder 1, 1953; MS110.001.010.00003 (Box 10)
  - Washington D.C.: Articles, Notes, Correspondence, Speeches, Folder 2, 1953 -- 1954; MS110.001.010.00004 (Box 10)
  - Washington D.C.: Declassified Documents, 1953 -- 1955; MS110.001.010.00005 (Box 10)
  - Washington/Sweden Transition: Embassy Correspondence, Articles, Press Releases, Folder 1, 1954; MS110.001.010.00006 (Box 10)
  - Washington/Sweden Transition: Embassy Correspondence, Articles, Press Releases, Folder 2, 1954; MS110.001.010.00007 (Box 10)
  - Washington/Brazil: Embassy Correspondence, 1961; MS110.001.010.00008 (Box 10)
  - Washington D.C.: Personal Correspondence, September - December, 1965; MS110.001.010.00009 (Box 10)
  - Washington D.C.: Personal Correspondence, 1966; MS110.001.010.00010 (Box 10)
  - Washington/Boston: Personal Correspondence -- Organizations, Donations, Receipts, Declassified Documents, Memberships, 1966; MS110.001.010.00011 (Box 10)
  - World War II, Threat of: Correspondence, 1938 -- 1942; MS110.001.010.00012 (Box 10)
  - Yugoslavia: Embassy Correspondence, Folder 1, 1945 -- 1948; MS110.001.010.00013 (Box 10)
  - Yugoslavia: Correspondence from Embassy, Folder 2, 1946 -- 1948; MS110.001.010.00014 (Box 10)
  - Yugoslavia: Belgrade - Correspondence, 1947; MS110.001.010.00015 (Box 10)
- Personal Records, 1946 -- 1969; MS110.002; 3.6 Linear Feet
  This series contains personal records of John Moors Cabot. Included are diaries, identification cards, passports, day planners, and audio-visual material.
  This series is arranged by record type, then chronologically.
  - Diaries 1-3, Oct.- Dec., 1946 -- 1947; MS110.002.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 4, Jan.- Dec., 1948; MS110.002.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 5-6, Jan.- Dec., 1949; MS110.002.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 7-8, Jan.- Dec., 1950 -- 1951; MS110.002.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 9, Jan.- Dec., 1952; MS110.002.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 10-11, Jan.- Dec., 1953; MS110.002.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 12-13, Jan.- Dec., 1954 -- 1955; MS110.002.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Diaries 14-16, Jan.- Jul., 1956 -- 1957; MS110.002.001.00008 (Box 1)
  - Diary 17, Jul.- Dec., 1957; MS110.002.001.00009 (Box 1)
  - Diary 18, Jan.- Jan., 1958 -- 1959; MS110.002.001.00010 (Box 1)
  - Diary 19, Jan.- Jan., 1959 -- 1960; MS110.002.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Diary 20, Jan.- May, 1960; MS110.002.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Diary 21, May- Oct., 1960; MS110.002.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Diary 22, Oct.- July, 1960 -- 1961; MS110.002.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Diary 23, July- May, 1960 -- 1962; MS110.002.002.00005 (Box 2)
    Also includes Dec. 1960 - Jan. 1961
  - Diary 24, May - April, 1962 -- 1963; MS110.002.002.00006 (Box 2)
  - Diary 25, April - May, 1963 -- 1964; MS110.002.002.00007 (Box 2)
  - Diary 26, May - June, 1964 -- 1965; MS110.002.002.00008 (Box 2)
  - Diary 27, June- Dec., 1965 -- 1966; MS110.002.002.00009 (Box 2)
  - Diaries 28-30, Dec.- May, 1966 -- 1969; MS110.002.002.00010 (Box 2)
  - Address Book, MS110.002.003.00001 (Box 3)
- Photographs, 1909 -- 1967; MS110.003; 7.2 Linear Feet
  This series contains photographs from John Cabot's time as an ambassador.
  This series is not arranged.
  - Riga, Guatemala, Holland, Sweden, Finland, Poland, U.S., 1938 -- 1940; MS110.003.001.00001 (Box 1)
  - Chile, Argentina, Germany, Yugoslavia, Greece, Turkey, Mexico, 1948; MS110.003.001.00002 (Box 1)
  - Yugoslavia, China, 1947 -- 1948; MS110.003.001.00003 (Box 1)
  - China, personal photos, 1948 -- 1950; MS110.003.001.00004 (Box 1)
  - China, South America, U.S., Finland, 1948 -- 1950; MS110.003.001.00005 (Box 1)
  - Finland, Venice, the Olympics, Mexico, Eisenhower Inaguration, Venezuela, 1952 -- 1953; MS110.003.001.00006 (Box 1)
  - Scrapbook of newspaper clippings and photos, Sweden, 1953; MS110.003.001.00007 (Box 1)
  - Eisenhower Inaguration, Central & South America, U.S., Sweden, Middle East, Greece, Egypt, 1953 -- 1954; MS110.003.002.00001 (Box 2)
  - Bolivia, formal event, 1953; MS110.003.002.00002 (Box 2)
  - Professional photos of state events, family members, 1938 -- 1954; MS110.003.002.00003 (Box 2)
  - Central and South America, 1957 -- 1959; MS110.003.002.00004 (Box 2)
  - Brazil, U.S., 1959 -- 1960; MS110.003.002.00005 (Box 2)
  - Brazil, 1960; MS110.003.003.00001 (Box 3)
  - Scrapbook of newsclippings, 1925 -- 1961; MS110.003.003.00002 (Box 3)
  - Isfahan (trip from Poland), Poland, 1962 -- 1965; MS110.003.003.00003 (Box 3)
  - Poland, U.S.S.R., Hungary, Romania, Bulgaria, Czechoslavokia, 1964; MS110.003.003.00004 (Box 3)
  - Poland, 1965; MS110.003.003.00005 (Box 3)
  - Poland, Holland, Mexico, U.S., Italy, 1964 -- 1965; MS110.003.003.00006 (Box 3)
  - Finland, Britain, Norway, Fiftieth Birthday party, 1951; MS110.003.004.00001 (Box 4)
  - Sweden, England, Spain, Denmark, Norway, U.S., 1955; MS110.003.004.00002 (Box 4)
  - John M. Cabot at Oxford, 1924; MS110.003.004.00003 (Box 4)
    Photograph of John M. Cabot with tennis team, Brasenose College, Oxford University.
  - Etching of Brasenose College, Oxford University, 1909; MS110.003.004.00004 (Box 4)
    Etching of Brasenose College found with photograph of J.M. Cabot, taken in 1924.
  - Brazil, U.S., 1960; MS110.003.005.00001 (Box 5)
  - Poland, England, U.S., War College trip to the Orient, Trip around the World--Japan, Cambodia, Thailand, India, Nepal, 1965 -- 1967; MS110.003.005.00002 (Box 5)
  - Loose Photos: Portraits, Central and South America, Sweden, Poland, 1932 -- 1952; MS110.003.006.00001 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: Central and South America, 1946 -- 1957; MS110.003.006.00002 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: Finland, 1950 -- 1953; MS110.003.006.00003 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: Uruguay and Milton Eisenhower's Visit, 1953; MS110.003.006.00004 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: Visit to El Salvador, 1953; MS110.003.006.00005 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: Dominican Republic, 1953; MS110.003.006.00006 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: National War College Trip to the Far East, 1953; MS110.003.006.00007 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: Venezuela, 1953; MS110.003.006.00008 (Box 6)
  - Loose Photos: Venezuela, Poland, 1953 -- 1964; MS110.003.006.00009 (Box 6)